goldpricez.com 2019-06-13

# The Privacy Policy - Gold Price Z

The website is owned and operated by GoldPriceZ.com. Your privacy is the most important to us. At GoldPriceZ.com, we want to make your involvement safe and satisfactory. While having a privacy notice is a legal obligation under the General Data Privacy Regulation (GDPR), we also offer this information for the purpose of transparency. 

## PRIVACY, TERMS, CONDITIONS AND COOKIES POLICY ETC 

The privacy of our visitors is important to us. We are fully aware about privacy of your personal information which is very important to us. This documents describes what types of personal information we record about users when visiting this website. In any case, we never sell or share your personal information to third parties. 

This is an informational website that diplay price information (on interbank market rates) of some commodities and currencies. We are not buying or selling any service from or to you (user). This website is for information purpose only, and not for commercial use. 

We collect prices from various external sources. 

We provide online rates of some commodities (e.g., Gold and Silver) in many weight units (e.g., Gram, Kg, Tola, Tael, Masha, Ratti, etc.) in all purity level in over 100 currencies of the world. The weight (or mass) of these units are calculated from Ounce and displayed on every page (e.g., 1 Gram Weight = 0.03210 Troy Ounce ). There might be deviation from the actual unit and weight appearing on this website. 

We are also providing free API for some commodities and currencies. While generating API key, the user requires to insert an email address, website URL, and his/her name. We may utilize these information in the future to communicate the subscriber regarding our services. We do not use their(subscriber) data for marketing purpose.   
In the future, we may stop this (or any other service) if we will wish to do so. 

Time of updation is appearing on every page. That is the time, on which we are pulling data from external sources. 

The gold price is being updated with 1-2 minute duration, while currency price with one-hour duration. 

We provide calculators for some commodities, it gives price estimation only. 

A user may contact us via email. We do not share your (user's) data (email address etc) with third-parties. 

For better user experience, we use information present in the log files temporarily (during session life time only). For example, IP(internet protocol) address, internet browser’s name, the name of their country, the timestamp of visiting our website and pages you browse while accessing our site. But we do not record those information in the database of goldpricez.com. Moreover, this website is hosted on third-party server i.e Namecheap, Inc. 

We use a cookie "gpz_seen-cookie" to show (or hide) consent message related to cookies usage and to record some information (mentioned below) for a good user experience. It is creating only when a user clicks on "X" link to close the consent message. Its lifetime is 365 days. Moreover, in future, we may record the following information in the mentioned cookie  
1\. parameter: utimezone, value=User browser's time zone offset. Purpose: To show commodities prices in user's relevant currency information. (It will be used in the future, currently unused).  
2\. parameter: lang, value=User browser's language. Purpose: To show price information in the users' language. (It will be used in the future, currently unused).  
3\. parameter: path, value=Default path.   
Note: Some browser's block javascript. In that case, the consent message will not display. 

We use the following third-party programs, they also use cookies and web beacons 

  * Google Analytics Service 
  * Google Adsense Service 
  * Media.Net 

They are placing and reading cookies on your browsers, or using web beacons to collect information.   
You can read more about these websites (e.g., working, web beacons, cookies etc) on their relavent websites.   
For more information about cookies and method of removing cookies from your computer (or handheld device, etc.), visit [ this (third-party) website ](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

We do not buy or sell any service or product directly, but purchases are made on external affiliate company websites (e.g., Amazon and etc): when a reader clicks on an affiliate link located on goldpricez.com to purchase an item, and the reader buys the item from the seller directly (not from the goldpricez.com). Affiliate companies pay goldpricez.com a small commission or other compensation for helping to bring customers to their website. 

A user can delete relevant data (if) recorded by GOLDPRICEZ.COM by sending email from the official email address or email address which recorded in our system to goldpricekg@gmail.com, and we will remove relevant information from our website within four weeks and will inform the user about deletion. We will not reply if we did not find any associated data. 

Gold Price signals are generated without human intervention using automated bio-inspired computational algorithms, which are trained using historical data of last 8 years. These algorithms are probabilistic in nature. It is for information puporse only. Therefore, be careful while using it for actual trading. 

## Legal Information and Terms of Use:

GoldPriceZ.com is not liable for any loss or damage arising out of the use of the data. GoldPriceZ.com indemnifies anyone against any third party claims of intellectual property rights for use of the data. 

We accept no claims as to the correctness, completeness, timeliness for any particular purpose any results produced by any of our services. 

If you (user) uses our data or any service, then you should acknowledge goldpricez.com. 

By using this website, you accept and agree to all terms and condition, legal information, privacy, and the disclaimer, etc., AND you also agree that we can update all information (including the terms and condition, privacy and disclaimer, anything) from time to time without notice to you. 

IN ADDITION TO ABOVE ALSO READ THE DISCLAIMER PAGE 

## YOUR CONSENT

If we required to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. 

You can contact us via email to ask any question related to our website, or suggest any changes, or report any problem or error etc. We appreciate your feedback. Our official email address is goldpricekg@gmail.com
